<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Wolfborn</name>
        <description>Wolfborn Race</description>
        <author>Arcanist's Archives</author>      
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="race-wolfborn.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/suncatsolari/woods/main/races/race-wolfborn.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Wolfborn" type="Race" source="Woods Approved Homebrew" id="ID_AA_WAH_RACE_WOLFBORN">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor"><i>"What is it, Fenrir?" Andraste asked softly. The mighty Wolfborn had his nose in the air, his nostrils flaring. He held a finger out so as to soothe her. "Orcs. And a lot of them." Fenrir drew his sword. "Stay close. It will be alright."</i><p>
            <p class="indent">-Denlys Warshadow,</p>
            <p class="indent"><i>The Roaming Pack</i></p>
            <p>Ancient werewolves, after evolving for hundreds of years, were refined into strong, cultured Wolfborn. These wolf-men are descendants of werewolves long forgotten. The Wolfborn are warriors, scholars, and friends.</p>
            <h4>DECEIVING APPEARANCE<h4>
            <p>Wolfborn are tall and muscular, standing over most humanoids. They range from about 6 feet to over 7 feet tall, weighing from 200 to 300 pounds. The Wolfborn are wolf like in appearance, with a long, bestial face and fur covering there bodies. Wolfborn can have black, gray, or white fur, just as wolves can. Wolfborn's sharp teeth and claws make them seem intimidating, but they are generally kind in nature. They have strangely colored eyes, including orange, blue, purple, and brown.</p>
            <h4>GENTLE GIANTS</h4>
            <p>Wolfborn are intimidating in appearance, but this does not carry over to their personalities. Almost all Wolfborn are kind and friendly, and do their best to form friendship with others. Wolfborn work best with others as a result of their ancient ancestors working in packs. Wolfborn are generally very selfless, putting others' needs first. They always try to help out the group, not just themselves.</p>
            <h4>NATURAL SURVIVORS<h4>
            <p>Wolfborn are natural experts at surviving in the wild. Their instincts are honed to the wild perfectly due to years of adaptation. Wolfborn will almost always help get others safe or fed first in a survival situation.</p>
            <h4>WOLFBORN NAMES</h4>
            <p>Wolfborn receive names from their parents. Wolfborn names are adapted from ancient names, or may be reminiscent of a wolf's sounds. Wolfborn that try to integrate themselves into others' culture may take one of that race's names. Wolfborn have two names; one given and one earned. If a Wolfborn has slain a great beast or done a great deed, it may take a second name relating to that.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Male Wolfborn Names:</strong> Amarok, Fenrir, Grimm, Lupin, Lycan, Magnus</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong>Female Wolfborn Names:</strong> Amarana, Freya, Kanastri, Nymeria, Vilka</p>
            <h4>WOLFBORN TRAITS<h4>
            <p>Your Wolfborn character has certain characteristics in common with all other Wolfborn.
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength score increases by 1, and one other ability score of your choice increases by one.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em> Wolfborn mature at a slightly quicker rate than humans, reaching adulthood at around 14 years of age, and live for about 80 years.</strong></p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Wolfborn tend to lean towards good or neutral alignments because of their kind nature. They try to lift others up and help everyone.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Wolfborn range from about 6 feet to over seven feet tall and have heavy builds. Your size is Medium.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</strong></p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> Due to your ancestors' time in the darkness, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Keen Senses.</em> The Wolfborn has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing and smell.</strong></p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Natural Weapons.</em> Your claws are unarmed weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal slashing damage equal to 1d6 plus your Strength modifier, instead of bludgeoning normal for an unarmed strike.</strong></p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em> You can speak, read, and write Common and one extra language of your choice.</strong></p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Subrace.</em> Three subraces of Wolfborn are found among the worlds of D&amp;D: Winter Wolfborn, Dire Wolfborn, and Gray Wolfborn. Choose one of these subraces.</strong></p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
        </sheet>                                            
    </element>
</elements>