<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="aasimar-mabaran.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/suncatsolari/Arcanists-Archive/master/homebrew/races/races-1/aasimar-mabaran.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>	
	<element name="Mabaran Aasimar" type="Sub Race" source="Exploring Eberron" id="ID_SUB_RACE_MABARAN_AASIMAR">
		<supports>Aasimar</supports>
		<description>
			<p>If your aasimar's powers flow from Mabar, you can use the fallen aasimar subrace from <em>Volo's Guide to Monsters</em>, but forgo the Healing Hands and Light Bearer traits, and instead use the following traits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Necrotic Shroud</em></strong> Starting at 3rd level, you can use your action to unleash the divine energy within yourself, causing your eyes to turn into pools of darkness and two skeletal, ghostly, flightless wings to sprout from your back. The instant you transform, other creatures within 10 feet of you that can see you must each succeed on a Charisma saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier) or become frightened of you until the end of your next turn. Your transformation lasts for 1 minute or until you end it as a bonus action. During it, once on each of your turns, you can deal extra necrotic damage to one target when you deal damage to it with an attack or a spell. The extra necrotic damage equals your level. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Consuming Touch.</em></strong> As an action, you can make a melee spell attack against a creature within your reach. On a hit, the target takes necrotic damage equal to your level and you regain hit points equal to half the damage dealt (round up). Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this trait.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Herald of Doom.</em></strong> You know the <em>toll the dead</em> cantrip. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for it.</p>
		</description>

		<sheet alt="Mabaran Aasimar" display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="1" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Custom Ability Score Improvement +1 (Mabaran Aasimar)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 1" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MABARAN_AASIMAR_NECROTIC_SHROUD" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MABARAN_AASIMAR_CONSUMING_TOUCH" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MABARAN_AASIMAR_SPIRIT_OF_FIRE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Necrotic Shroud" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MABARAN_AASIMAR_NECROTIC_SHROUD">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your action to unleash the divine energy within yourself, causing your eyes to turn into pools of darkness and two skeletal, ghostly, flightless wings to sprout from your back. The instant you transform, other creatures within 10 feet of you that can see you must each succeed on a Charisma saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier) or become frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your transformation lasts for 1 minute or until you end it as a bonus action. During it, once on each of your turns, you can deal extra necrotic damage to one target when you deal damage to it with an attack or a spell. The extra necrotic damage equals your level.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>The instant you transform, other creatures within 10 feet of you that can see you must each succeed on a Charisma saving throw (DC {{necrotic shroud:dc}}) or become frightened of you until the end of your next turn. Your transformation lasts for 1 minute or until you end it as a bonus action. During it, once on each of your turns, you can deal {{level}} extra necrotic damage to one target when you deal damage to it with an attack or a spell.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="necrotic shroud:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="necrotic shroud:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="necrotic shroud:dc" value="charisma:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Consuming Touch" type="Racial Trait" source="Exploring Eberron" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MABARAN_AASIMAR_CONSUMING_TOUCH">
		<description>
			<p>As an action, you can make a melee spell attack against a creature within your reach. On a hit, the target takes necrotic damage equal to your level and you regain hit points equal to half the damage dealt (round up). Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this trait.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>Your transformation lasts for 1 minute or until you end it as a bonus action. During it, you shed bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet, and at the end of each of your turns, you and each creature within 10 feet of you take {{level:half:up}} fire damage. In addition, once on each of your turns, you can deal {{level}} extra fire damage to one target when you deal damage to it with an attack or a spell.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Spirit of Fire" type="Racial Trait" source="Exploring Eberron" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_FERNIAN_AASIMAR_SPIRIT_OF_FIRE">
		<description>
			<p>You know the produce flames cantrip. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for it.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You know the produce flames cantrip. (Spellcasting: Charisma)</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRODUCE_FLAME" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</element>